Now bring it!
（西谷(にしのや)夕(ゆう)）さ来い
He got it up!
（烏野(からすの)一同）上がた
I'm gonna go show Ushiwaka who's boss!
（日向(ひなた)翔陽(しょうよう)）ウシワカ
ギャフンと言わせたらあ
（影山(かげやま)飛雄(とびお)）あ
（日向）は
If you want to beat Wakatoshi,
you're gonna have to beat me first.
（天童(てんどう)覚(さとり)）若利(わかとし)君を倒したければ
俺を倒してから行け
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
Episode Three:
The Guessing Monster
Whoa...
（男性）うわあ出たあ
The Guessing Monster makes his appearance.
ゲス･モンスタ
（田中(たなか)冴子(さえこ)）ん
What do they mean by that?
（冴子）ゲスて何
白鳥沢の５番ゲス野郎なの
Does he scare people by guessing
their name correctly or something?
I-Is he going to poke them in the eyes or something?
（谷地(やち)仁花(ひとか)）め目つぶしとか
してくるのかな
Be careful, Hinata!
気をつけて日向
That'd be cheating.
（嶋田(しまだ)誠(まこと)）それじゃあ反則だね
（ホイスル）
Give us a good one, Leon!
(れおん)さんナイサ
(れおん)）てい
（澤村(さわむら)大地(だいち)）うすまん
Sorry!
Finish it off, Kageyama!
（田中(たなか)龍之介(りゅうのすけ)）影山ラスト
Stop them again!
（男子生徒）もう１本止めたれ
Blocking isn't about stopping the ball.
ブロクはさあ
止める技術じゃないよ
Tsutomu, cover the straight spike.
工ストレトしめて
（影山）う
It's a technique to smack down the ball.
（天童）たたき落とす技術だよ
（ホイスル）
Be Courageous Warriors
All right!
（白鳥沢一同）よしゃ
（谷地）うう
When you're able to get a clean block off,
やぱブロクは
きれいに決まれば—
it truly is a technique that makes
you feel like the tables have turned.
それだけで
精神的一発逆転の必殺技だな
（天童）くう
I'm starting to get into it!
ノてきたあ
Get the next one!
（山口(やまぐち)忠(ただし)）次１本
Shake it off, Kageyama!
ドンマイ影山君
ドントマインド
Shake, shake it off! Kageyama!
あ影山
（影山）ふん
Karasuno                 Shiratorizawa
（ホイスル）
（大平）ふん
（澤村）ん
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
（天童）おお
（五色）ん
So naive.
あめわ
（西谷）ああくう
（ホイスル）
All right!
（白鳥沢一同）よしゃ
（天童）ああ
I'm playing at 120% today!
今日の俺120点
How is he able to react like that?
何であんな反応できんの
（嶋田）反応だけじゃない
It's not just his reaction.
In that moment, there were three possibilities.
今の一瞬の攻防の中に最低でも
３つの読み合いがあた
Net
First, Kageyama's in the front row currently,
so it was possible for him to do a setter dump.
まず今影山は前衛だから
ツアタクが可能なわけで—
So he had to consider that.
ツなのか否か
Net
If he wasn't going to do a dump,
ツじゃない場合
前衛の田中日向—
he could've set to Tanaka or Hinata in the front row
and Azumane or Sawamura in the back row.
後衛の東峰(あずまね)澤村誰を使うのか
And in this case, he picked Hinata,
そして日向に
上がたわけだが
but there were also a few places Hinata could've spiked it.
日向がどのコスを狙うのか
You can see quite a bit from up here,
こうやて上から見てると
いろいろ分かるけどさ—
but when you're on the court,
you can get lost in the chaos easily.
実際コトにいると
混乱もするし—
So even if you know which way you want to go,
your body may not move right.
頭で分かてても
動けなかたりすんだよな
But his body can do it.
でもアイツは動けてる
（ブザ
I guess it's no surprise that they took a timeout.
（滝ノ上(たきのうえ)祐輔(ゆうすけ)）さすがに
タイムアウト取たな
I totally thought that they were going to do a back row attack just now.
（五色）俺今絶対
バクアタクだと思いましたよ
I mean, he gave that other guy a look.
だてちらと
見たじゃないですか
That was a total fake out.
あれは完全フェイク
（五色）え
Huh?
Karasuno's setter's pretty good, right?
烏野のセタ
相当うまいヤツだろ
Yet that glance was way too obvious and over the top.
なのにあの視線は
わざとらしすぎ
Glances, footwork, and ball handling...
（白布(しらぶ)賢二郎(けんじろう)）視線足ハンドリング
どんな動きでも—
If Tendou figures any of those things out, you're finished.
天童さんに悟られたら
おしまいだよ
Nice block, Satori.
（斉藤(さいとう)明(あきら)）
ナイスブロク覚
Thanks.
（天童）はい若利君
俺のほうが目立てごめんねえ
Sorry that I'm getting more attention than you, Wakatoshi.
（牛島(うしじま)若利(わかとし)）ん問題ない
That's not a problem.
We're going to stop them here!
（澤村）次１本切るぞ
Hinata, we're going to switch things up! Get this next one!
（田中）日向切り替えだぞ
次決めたれ
Right!
（日向）おす
おお
（田中）うあ
Hey, Kageyama, what's wrong with your face?
おい影山顔どうした
Nothing's wrong.
どうもしないす
（田中）ウソつけ
You liar!
It's one thing when my spike gets blocked,
（影山）自分がスパイク
止められるより—
but it pisses me off a million times more when a spike from my set gets blocked.
自分のセトアプからの
スパイク止められるほうが—
100万倍腹立つ
How is their number five able to keep blocking like that?
（武田(たけだ)一鉄(いてつ)）あの５番何でこうも
続け様にブロクを
You remember read blocking, right?
（鳥養(うかい)繋心(けいしん)）先生リドブロクは
分かるよな
You see where the set is going
before jumping up to block, right?
トスがどこに上がるのか見てから
跳ぶブロクですね
Yeah.
ああリドは
“読む”て意味じゃなく—
"Read" in this case doesn't necessarily mean to see
it coming, but more to understand your opponent.
“理解する”的な意味だ
Since you're jumping up after watching the ball,
there's no danger in the set tricking you.
ボルを見てから跳ぶんで
トスに振られる危険はない
Your reaction will be slightly slower, but if you can make up for that by using three blockers, it's the most effective.
反応は若干遅れるが
そこをブロク３人で—
ちゃんと連携できれば
最も万能といえる
We're still trying to learn this technique.
俺たちは絶賛練習中だがな
On the other hand, what's special about number five
それに対して
あの５番のブロクの特徴は—
is his reading and intuition.
読みと直感
ゲス･ブロクだ
He does guess blocking.
"Guess" means to presume something.
〝ゲス〞つのは
推測て意味で—
He'll read the attack before the set goes up,
and then he'll jump pretty much on intuition.
トスが上がる前に
攻撃を読み—
ほぼ直感で跳ぶ
Guess?!
Of course, there'll be times where his intuition is off,
当然直感が外れることもあるし
下手をやれば—
and he might get in the way of his team's blocks and receives.
味方ブロクやレシブを
邪魔しかねない
This is definitely a style of blocking that doesn't work for everyone.
あくまで個人技頼みなブロクだ
That said, I think he's so accurate
with his guesses that it's scary.
があの５番その読みが
恐ろしく鋭いんだと思う
On top of that, his body can react to those guesses.
そしてその読みに反応できる
体を持ている
It's better to think that his movements have no regularity to them.
ヤツの動きに規則性はないと
思たほうがいい
Don't overthink it and get fooled by him.
考えすぎて惑わされんなよ
（烏野部員たち）おす
Yes, sir!
（ブザ
What do we need to do in order for him not to read our sets?
トスを読まれないためには
どうすればいいのかな
Does that mean Kageyama's going to have to do those crazy decoy moves that Hinata does too?
日向みたいに
めちゃくちゃなフェイントを—
影山も入れるとか
I wouldn't mind seeing that.
（月島(つきしま)蛍(けい)）
おもしろくていいんじゃない
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
（ホイスル）
Give us another good serve!
（天童）もう１本ナイサ
（大平）てい
Up front!
（東峰(あずまね)旭(あさひ)）前前
（澤村）うう
Sorry! It's short!
すまん短い
It doesn't matter how you try to fake Tendou out.
（白布）どんなフェイクを
入れようとも天童さんは
So this must be what it means to have perfect coordination.
（天童）“一糸乱れぬ”て
こういう感じを言うのね
（影山）う
I just barely missed it.
（天童）ギリギリ
（ホイスル）
Yeah!
（一同）しゃ
Go, go, Karasuno! Push it, push it, Karasuno!
（応援団）いけいけ烏野
押せ押せ烏野
I had no idea where the set was going to go until after he landed the spike.
（白布）スパイクが決まるまで
どこに上がるか—
またく分からなかた
You aimed that to go right over my head after what I just did, didn't you?
（天童）さきの今で俺の頭の
ド真上ぶち抜いてくるなんて—
You must really hate losing.
相当な負けず嫌いだねえ
ウフやぱお前ら
おもしれえ
You guys really are amusing.
Japanese National High School Volleyball Tournament
（西谷）チャンスボル
Here's a chance to score!
（影山）ふ
（天童）は
間違えた
I've made a mistake!
（澤村）う
（山形(やまがた)隼人(はやと)）う
Let's try again!
（澤村）もかいもかい
（西谷）しゃう
Okay!
Got it!
オライ
It's better to think that his movements have no regularity to them.
（繋心）ヤツの動きに
規則性はないと思たほうがいい
Don't overthink it and get fooled by him.
考えすぎて惑わされんなよ
And with opponents like this,
それとこういう相手こそ—
it's best to lead them as far left or right as possible.
左右の横幅目いぱいだ
You just don't stop moving, do you?
よく動くことよ
（日向）せい
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
（ホイスル）
（烏野一同）しゃ
All right!
Yes! We caught up!
（菅原(すがわら)孝支(こうし)）よしゃブレイク
Nice spike, Hinata!
（縁下(えんのした)力(ちから)）日向ナイスキ
（山口）おお
Way to go, Hinata!
いいぞ日向
（日向）うおお
（天童）ハァ
There have been setters who I admired for trying
so hard to stop me from reading their moves,
思わず見とれちゃうような
読ませないセタは—
今まで何人か見たけどさあ
but that number ten's timing sure is fast.
あの10番のタイミングの
早(はえ)えことよ
If I'm even one tempo late, I can't get it.
ほんのワンテンポ遅れれば
もう届かない
Were you just expecting us to forget your
"I've made a mistake!" from earlier?
さきの“間違えた”は
スルの方向かな
Ayup, I guess...
さいでゲス
（牛島）語尾が変だぞ天童
You're talking strangely, Tendou.
（ホイスル）
Give us another good serve, Kageyama!
（田中）影山もう１本
ナイサ
（影山）ううう
（山形）く
Nice receive!
（白布）
ナイスレシブう
（五色）う
（東峰）う
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
（嶋田）攻撃のチャンスだ
This is their chance to attack!
く
（田中）う
ワンタチ
I hit it!
（影山）うう
Got it!
（山形）オライ
（白布）う
Be Courageous Warriors
Did he try to fake me out?
（影山）今まさか
フェイクを入れたのか
Or did he just change his mind?
それとも単に気が変わただけ
（冴子･谷地）うう
（月島(つきしま)明光(あきてる)）白鳥沢てホント—
It really seems like conventional logic
doesn't work on Shiratorizawa.
理屈が通じない相手て感じだな
（天童）快感
Just what is with number five's blocking?
一体何なんでしょう
あの５番のブロク
He's planning on stopping all of them on his own.
アイツは全部１人で止める気だ
（武田）え
Huh?
Tendou's blocks are basically blocks used to score points.
（繋心）天童のブロクは
いわば点を決めるためのブロク
He uses his opponent's spikes against them to score himself.
相手のスパイクをそのまま
ひくり返して自分の点にしちまう
But there's more to blocking than just that.
だがな単品で決めることだけが
ブロクのすべてじゃない
今俺たちがやろうとしている
つなぐためのブロクも—
The way we block to keep the ball in play
can score points too if we get it to work.
決まてくれば得点に結びつく
In any case, depending on the timing,
blocks can actually be more valuable than spikes.
いずれにしろブロクてのは
決まるタイミングによては—
スパイク以上の価値があるんだ
I see.
なるほど
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
（日向）うう
Nice receive!
うう離されるなよ
Don't let them pull away!
Ushijima!
If you give them an opening, they're not going to stop!
きかけつかまれたら
一気に持てかれんぞ
（牛島）ふん
（ホイスル）
Nice spike, Ushijima!
（菅原）く
（嶋田）ああ
That was like a spike to shut up the commoners.
Ushijima! Ushijima!
（男性）
庶民を黙らす１発て感じ
Ushiwaka's definitely on another level.
（男性）ウシワカはやぱ
次元が違(ちげ)えなあ
In order to stop attacks, blocks evolve.
攻撃を防ぐために
ブロクは進化し—
And in order to break through blocks, attacks also evolve.
ブロクを破るために—
攻撃もまた進化する
（繋心）あ
Attacks become diverse by using the back row,
getting faster, and players working in combination.
（武田）バクアタク
攻撃の高速化—
コンビネションと
攻撃は多様化され—
するとブロクも—
And then by changing how one jumps and where one jumps from, blocks shut down attacks.
取り方やその配置を変化させ
攻撃を打ち破る
They think they're at the top, but they continue
to develop and reach even higher heights.
ここが頂点と思た場所から—
さらに上さらに上へと
開拓してきた
Looks like you've learned a few things, sir.
勉強したな先生
（武田）言葉だけです
Those are just words.
I'm sure they kept developing through understanding,
their fighting spirit, and unwavering tenacity.
きと不屈の闘志とド根性の下(もと)
理性で開拓してきたんだ
All right!
While miraculous plays save the team,
ミラクルでスパなプレは
チムを救いますが—
それは理性も同じです
the same can be said about improving their understanding.
Karasuno                 Shiratorizawa
Oh?
（天童）お
普通のほう
Hey, it's the normal guy.
（月島）ん
（澤村）はいあおられない
Okay. Don't let him get to you.
（ホイスル）
Give us a good serve!
（大平）ナイサ
（西谷）あ落ちる
It's dropping!
（西谷）うりゃ
Here's our chance!
（川西(かわにし)太一(たいち)）
チャンスボルチャンスボル
Damn it! I'm sorry!
クソすんません
（白布）う
A delayed attack?
（影山）１人時間差
Huh?
（武田･繋心）うお
Tsukki!
Yes!
（烏野一同）すげえ
Hi. I'm the normal guy.
（月島）どうも普通のほうです
（天童）へ
A delayed attack may've fooled our wild beast
over there, but it doesn't work on me.
１人時間差
うちの野生児はだませても
僕には通じないんで—
It's a pleasure to meet you.
よろしくどうぞ
I knew that all you Karasuno first-years pissed me off, but you take the cake!
烏野の１年
腹立つヤツばかだと思たら—
お前断トツ
Thank you.
どうも
（天童）腹立つ
Screw you, man!
（ホイスル）
Give us a good serve, Asahi!
（田中）旭さんナイサ
（東峰）うう
（山形）う
（白布）ふ
（天童）う
（ホイスル）
（応援団員）ナイスキ牛島
Nice spike, Ushijima!
Please don't stop thinking.
（武田）考え続けてください
Ushijima! Ushijima!
Be Karasuno's understanding.
烏野の理性
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
Karasuno High School vs Shiratorizawa Academy
Haikyuu
!!
（山口）必ず
（日向）ん
I'll definitely...
必ずチャンスは来るよ
I'll definitely get my chance.
（繋心）くくんん
（山口）俺に
行かせてください
Please put me in. Please put me in. Please put me in.
山口が—
Yamaguchi's projecting a tremendous aura.
すげえ念送てくる
（武田）え
俺に
行かせてください
Huh?
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
ワンチ
（天童）チ
I touched it!
オライう
Got it!
（影山）ふ
（田中）くう
（牛島）う
（白布）う
I hit it!
（月島）ワンチ
（白布）うとうしい
So annoying.
We can score here!
（東峰）
チャンスボル
（田中）くう
（五色･山形）あ
（ホイスル）
Yeah!
That was all yours, Tsutomu! You idiot!
（鷲匠(わしじょう)鍛冶(たんじ)）
今のは工だべやバカが
If you're gonna stare at someone, at least stare at a girl!
（鷲匠）見合いなら女とやれや
ううあはい
Y-Yes, sir!
（五色）プ“はい”て
Pfft... "Yes, sir."
I don't care if you run into each other! Go for the damn ball, ya idjits!
出たな鬼監督
And there's the demon coach.
今日は静かだと思てたのに
I thought he was gonna stay quiet today.
（日向･西谷）ソイ
Yeah!
（ブザ
Karasuno                 Shiratorizawa
（ホイスル）
（澤村）スガナイサ
Give us a good serve, Suga!
Leon, up front!
前
（大平）う
（澤村）う
Switch places!
（影山）スイチ
（菅原）からの
And then...
a synchronized attack!
シンクロ攻撃
（白布･天童･大平）ああ
（影山）だあ
（ホイスル）
Yeah!
しゃ
（菅原）ナイス影山
Nice, Kageyama!
What?! What happened just now?!
（横山(よこやま)静康(しずやす)）何だ
今のは誰がどうした
セタが打たのか
Did the setter just spike?!
がこざかしい
孫の代になても変わんねえな
Those crafty bastards...
I guess things haven't changed,
even with the grandson in charge.
Oh, right. Karasuno's coach is Coach Ukai's grandson.
（斉藤）ああ烏野のコチは
烏養先生のお孫さんでしたね
Ukai...
烏養
He always did think that doing
new things was the key to success.
昔から新しいことこそが
強さだと思ている
I never did like him.
いけ好かねえ男だわ
Shiratorizawa                  Karasuno
（鳥養(うかい)一繋(いけい)）
常にレフトの
大砲頼みとは原始的な
Always relying on the left-handed cannon is archaic.
全員で攻撃なんて
ムチャやるから—
Your team is ridiculous and has everyone attack,
so no one's there to give backup!
フォロも何にも
できんのだろうが
There're only a certain number of things you can do
with these high school teams that change every year.
高校つう
毎年入れ替わるチムで—
やれることなんて限られるわ
よい素材をよい形で磨くことが
Polishing the diamonds in the rough as best you can...
（大平）せい
（菅原）う
（ホイスル）
All right!
（白鳥沢一同）よしゃ
...is the best possible option.
（鷲匠）効率的な道だ
鷲匠先生は昔から変わんねえ
Coach Washijou never changes.
（武田）え
Oohira! Oohira
シンプル･イズ･ベスト
高さとパワを愛し—
"Simple is best."
He loves tall and powerful players,
and he's always on the lookout for talent.
いつもアンテナを張り巡らせて
強い選手を見い出し集める
君ナイサ
Give us a good one, Leon.
（繋心）たとえ元のチムで
はじかれた者だたとしても—
Even if they weren't accepted by the team originally,
（ホイスル）
if they fit Coach Washijou's definition
of "skilled," there won't be a problem.
鷲匠先生の強さの基準に
はまれば関係ない
そしてスパルタと練習量で
ひたすら個を鍛える
And then he puts them through
hardcore training to get them in shape.
でもみんながスタ選手とは
いかないですよね
But you can't call all of them star players, can you?
Of course not.
もちろんだ
牛島みたいなヤツは—
Though I'm sure finding someone like
Ushijima was like hitting the jackpot.
１人入てきただけで
大当たりだろうけどな
牛島みたいな主力選手を—
Using a powerful player like Ushijima as the main attacker
and making sure that no one gets in his way...
Ushijima!
文字どおり軸として
それらを邪魔しないのが
（ホイスル）
（繋心）
白鳥沢のスタイルなんじゃねえかな
probably sums up Shiratorizawa's style.
All right!
くはやぱウシワカ
止まんねえなあ
Ushiwaka really doesn't let up.
でも流れを引き寄せる手段は
まだ残てる
But there are still ways to turn things around.
（冴子）あ
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
（白布）う
（ホイスル）
All right!
Karasuno                    Shiratorizawa
（白鳥沢一同）
しゃ
Nice spike, Tsutomu!
（山形）
ナイスキ工
Give us a good serve, Shirabu!
（五色）白布さんナイサ
（ホイスル）
（白布）う
オライ
Got it!
（日向）てい
（ホイスル）
（烏野一同）よしゃ
（白布）うう
All right!
翔陽ナイス
Nice one, Shouyou!
うう緊張で心臓が痛い
I have a headache from all this stress...
俺も痛い
（嶋田）あ
So do I...
（ブザ
俺がいればお前は最強だ
As long as I'm around, you're invincible!
（山口）俺はあんなに
自信満々なこと言えないけど
I could never say something that confident,
（ホイスル）
（山口）
力を貸せるところまでは来たよ
but I've gotten to the point where I can be helpful.
Give us a good serve.
ナイサ
フフゥ
うくう
Their formation broke!
崩した
（繋心）よし
Good!
（山口）チャンスは必ず
My chance will definitely...
すいません
（山形）若利
Sorry!
Wakatoshi!
止めんぞ
（東峰）おう
Let's stop him!
Yeah!
（牛島）いい
高いトス１つあればそれでいい
Good.
I just need one high set.
くくうう
（ホイスル）
（応援団員）ナイスキ牛島
Be Courageous Warriors
Nice spike, Ushijima!
これが強いということだわ
Ushijima! Ushijima!
This is what it means to be good.
（ブザ
（天童）バキバキに折れ
Keep on breaking them!
何を心をだよ
What, you say? Their hearts!
粉々に砕け
Keep on shattering them!
What, you say?
何を
（瀬見(せみ)英太(えいた)）ん
（瀬見）んブロク
Their blocks?
Nah, their spirits!
精神をだよ
Keep on breaking them...
（瀬見）相変わらず読めね
I can never read this guy.
（天童）くう
しつけえなあメガネ小僧
That brat with the glasses sure is persistent.
先生
（武田）はい
If you would, sir.
Right.
（ブザ
サブでお膳立てされても
止めらんねえのかよ
Apparently, even that serve isn't enough to stop them.
Yeah.
When they're able to stop ‘em, they can,
and when they can't stop ‘em, they can't! Got it?!
止まる時は止まるし—
止まんねえ時は
止まんねえんだよおい
（繋心）ああいうどシャトや
３枚ブロクぶち抜きは—
It's true that completely shutting them down or
breaking through a three-person block looks cool,
できたら確かにカコいい
盛り上がりもするしな
and it excites the crowd,
でも完結させたがるなよ
but don't try to end the rally.
苦しい時ほど１発で—
I'm sure that the rougher things get,
the more you'll want to end things in one shot.
完結させたくなるだろうが—
But don't forget to imagine how the rally could continue,
whether it's making some contact or going for a rebound.
ワンタチリバウンド—
次のプレをイメジすることを
忘れるな
すべてのプレはつながている
It's all about keeping the ball in play.
This doesn't mean you're supposed to put up your guard.
守りに入れてことじゃ
ねえからな
I know that!
分かてし
しつこく言うが直接
点になていないプレも—
I know I'm repeating myself, but even if a play doesn't
work out, keeping at it will produce results eventually.
あとあと効いてくる
せかくの５セトマチだ
We're finally playing a best-of-five.
It'd be a waste to spend the whole time
dreading how long you've still got.
ただ“長くてしんどいなあ”とだけ
思て戦うなんて—
もたいねえだろ
（一同）ヘヘフフ
（ブザ
しゃいくか
（日向）おす
Right! Let's do this!
Yeah!
（月島）あの
（日向）お
Um...
（月島）３枚ブロクの時の
タイミング—
Would you let me handle the timing
僕に任せてもらえませんか
for the three-person block?
（瀬見）白布
（白布）ん
Shirabu.
若利の配分ちゃんと考えろよ
Don't forget to pass to Wakatoshi.
（白布）はい大丈夫です
Right. Got it.
That little shit!
かわいくねえ
（天童）まあまあまあ
Now, now.
（ホイスル）
（大平）ナイサ工
（五色）フゥ
Give us a good one, Tsutomu!
（東峰）大地
（澤村）うおし
Daichi!
Yeah!
（五色）クソあの１番毎回
Damn it! That number one is there every single time!
（東峰）ええい
（ホイスル）
Karasuno                   Shiratorizawa
All right!
（烏野一同）
しゃ
Give us a good serve, Daichi!
（田中）大地さんナイサ
（ホイスル）
（澤村）う
Tsutomu!
工
（五色）はい
Right!
（白布）ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
（川西）う
I hit it!
ワンチ
（田中）うあ
Ryuu!
龍(りゅう)
（谷地）つないだ
He kept the rally going!
ナイスタイミング
ナイスワンチだ
Nice timing! And nice contact!
Keep it going!
つなげつなげ
（澤村）うう
牛島ホント止まんねえな
Ushijima just won't stop.
烏野のコチ何を喜んでんだよ
What's Karasuno's coach so happy about?
全然止まてねえじゃん
（東峰）オライふ
They haven't stopped him at all.
Got it!
チャンスボル
We can score here!
（白布）う
（川西）ふ
（大平）ふん
（澤村）あ
（ホイスル）
（冴子･谷地）うう
Nice spike, Oohira!
（応援団員）ナイスキ大平
Oohira!
（白鳥沢応援団）大平
Karasuno                  Shiratorizawa
（山形）
太一ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Taichi!
（ホイスル）
（川西）いくぞ
Here I go!
（田中）うぐ
（月島）う
（白布）う
Nice receive, Shirabu!
（大平）とさに
セタを狙たな
He hit it at the setter on the spur of the moment.
（大平）若利
Wakatoshi!
（繋心）囲い込め重要なのは
ブロクの面積とタイミング
Cage him in!
What's important is the block's breadth and timing!
壁を意識させろ
Imagine a wall!
Here we go. Please take it slow.
いきますゆくりせ
Ready, and...
go!
And waiting where it breaks through...
（繋心）そして抜けた先には
（繋心）スパリベロ
is our super libero!
すべてのプレはつながている
Everything they do is connected!
（天童）セト終盤
やと上がた貴重なレシブ
The set's nearing its end.
They finally got this important receive up.
絶対こち
It's gotta be... over here!
マジかよ
Seriously?
（月島）う
（天童）ぐぐうう
（ホイスル）
（一同）よしゃ
All right!
（一同）うわあ
Yeah!
フやときれいに決またな
They finally executed it perfectly.
トタルディフェンス
Total defense.
さあここからだ
Now...
Karasuno                    Shiratorizawa
it's finally begun!
Keep on breaking them!
（天童）バキバキに折れ
What, you say? Their hearts!
何を心をだよ
Keep on shattering them! What, you say?
粉々に砕け
Their spirits, right?
何を
（瀬見）精神だろ
Nah, their will!
（天童）気力をだよ
They both mean the same thing!
Episode Four:
The Halo Around the Moon
（瀬見）
どれも同じじゃねえか
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
"The Halo Around the Moon."
次回「ハイキュ」